Good morning there.
您好
May I
请问
have your name please?
您怎么称呼
Good morning.
您好
I'm Tu Xiaoning.
涂筱柠
Miss Tu.
涂小姐
Nice to meet you.
您好 您好
Here.
来
Here's your Number Bear.
请领取您爱的号码熊
If you meet your Mr. Right,
如果啊遇到心仪的男士
you can exchange
可以凭借
the bears of yours
您和对方的小熊
for
来兑换
a bigger one.
我们的这个大熊噢
Feel free to ask me
那如果有什么需要的话
if you need help.
可以叫我
This way, please.
您 里边请
At the age of 27,
二十七岁这一年
I have two
我有两件
big life events to accomplish.
人生大事要完成
This is one of them.
眼前就是其中一件
But when I get really into
但当我真正卷入
the dating market,
相亲市场后
reality slaps me in the face
现实却一次次
over and over again.
给我扇着响亮的巴掌
Mismatch exists forever in the needs
相亲市场的男男女女
between men and women here.
需求总是不匹配
Good morning, Miss.
女士您好
What's your number?
请问您是几号呢
No. 36.
三十六
This way, please.
那请跟我来
My annual salary is in the eight figures.
我的年薪现在是八位数
I want my future partner
我希望我的未来伴侣
to be able and tough as me.
能跟我是强强联合的
When we get married, we should
这相亲成功后啊
prepare for pregnancy as soon as possible.
我希望咱俩能尽快备孕
After all, you're 27 years old.
这毕竟你也二十七了
Right?
是吧
Just six years younger than me.
就 就比我小六岁
I thought
还以为这样的
I'd have more possibilities
车轮战相亲
with incessant bind dates.
会遇到更多的可能
Sir.
先生
Here's your Number Bear.
请领取您爱的号码熊
If you meet your Ms. Right,
如果遇到心仪的女士
you can exchange
可以凭借您
the bears of yours
和对方的小熊
for
来我们这
this big bear.
兑换这个大熊噢
Just keep it up.
再接再厉吧
I'll try my luck on evening session.
只能等晚上了
Hello.
你好
Let me introduce myself.
那我先自我介绍一下
I work at a bank.
我是在银行工作
I just returned from abroad a while ago.
前段时间刚刚回国
I'm still struggling
这段时间
to fit in.
还在适应和调整
I was abroad
我也有
for my study, too.
在国外留学的经历
But
不过
I've been back for over three years.
已经回国三年多了
Now I'm working for a state-owned company.
现在呢是在国企工作
If you need
如果你有什么
any help,
需要帮忙的
you can call me.
都可以找我
What a good match.
真配呀
You work
你是在
in a bank?
银行工作
So, you studied financial management?
那你学的是金融管理
My undergraduate degree is
本科在国内
in business management in China.
读的是企业管理
I went to graduate school abroad
研究生在国外
for finance.
读的是金融
I went to graduate school
我研究生
for business management, too.
读的是企业管理
What a coincidence.
真的好巧啊
What do you think of me?
你觉得我怎么样
This pair should be a done deal.
这对应该成了
Sorry.
抱歉啊
I need to reconsider.
我还需要再考虑一下
Reconsider?
再考虑一下
Can't find a match, even for good ones, huh?
这么优质还对不齐需求
I think we can get to know
我觉得我们
each other a little better.
可以再了解一下
What am I waiting for?
还在这儿等什么呢
Long time no see.
好久不见
Tu Xiaoning.
涂筱柠
Ji,
纪
Ji Yuheng?
纪昱恒
At this moment I do not know,
这一刻的我还不知道
the parallel lines
那看似
that seemingly have no intersection
没有交集的平行线
are about to curve.
早已悄悄地转了弯
Here.
来
Thank you.
谢谢
It has been years.
这么多年过去了
Where are you working at now?
你现在在哪儿工作呢
Internal Controls and Compliance Department.
代瑞总行
Bank of Dairui Head Office.
内控合规部
Such a coincidence.
这么巧
You're at Dairui, too?
你也在代瑞啊
The Internal Controls and Compliance Department.
内控合规部
It's responsible for auditing,
就是银行内部
supervising,
负责审查
and anti-money laundering
监管
within the bank.
反洗钱的那个部门
Exactly.
正是
If I fall into
那万一以后
your hands,
我落到你手里
please
你要
have mercy on me.
对我手下留情啊
I don't know.
说不准
I might be stricter to you.
可能会更严格呢
Then, I
那我要打起
have to be
十二分精神来了
on my toes.
可千万不能犯错
It's been a long time.
这么久不见了
How about
我们
we exchange WeChat number?
加个微信吧
What do you say?
方便吗
Sure.
当然
I'll scan your QR Code.
我来扫你吧
Okay.
好
Do we have to be so even?
要算那么清楚吗
It's a rule of blind dating.
这是相亲的规矩
Splitting the bill.
我们平摊费用
I'm comfortable with that.
我比较安心
If we have a chance to meet again,
如果下次见面的话
as an old classmate,
作为老同学
I can buy you the meal.
我可以请你
If that's the case,
那看起来
I seem to have failed this time.
我似乎相亲失败了
Not completely.
不完全算
We got the big bear.
有这个
It's just
算
half failure.
失败一半
Weiyi.
惟依
What's up?
怎么了
How was it?
怎么样啊
I haven't heard from you all afternoon.
一下午没消息
Nothing.
没怎么样
Aren't there hundreds of people
不是大型相亲聚会
at the dating rally?
几百号人吗
You haven't found even one of
一根能抓的救命稻草
those fish?
都没有
No.
没有
I should've gone with you.
早知道我陪你去了
I can't believe
那么多男人
there's not even one
我就不信
suitable man out there.
没有一个能抓的
Well, not exactly.
也不能说完全没有
There is one.
倒是有一个
But
不过
he's a special case,
他情况特殊
so he can be ignored.
可以忽略不计
"Special"?
特殊
What kind of "special"?
有多特殊啊
I'll tell you later.
回头再跟你说吧
Better go now.
我先挂了啊
Oh my God!
救命啊
It's so embarrassing!
太社死了
It's already too much to meet a high school
相亲遇到高中同学
classmate on a blind date.
也就算了
Now I have to count on his car
还得用人家的车
to take my scooter!
拉着我骑过来的小电驴
I must have been out of my mind
我刚才答应的时候
when I said yes.
脑子一定是抽了
I don't think this scooter
看这个情况
can get you back.
应该是骑不回去了
How about I drive you home?
还是我送你吧
So,
那
is this the safe place
放在这
to put a scooter?
会丢吗
Ji Yuheng.
纪昱恒
Why don't you
要不
put me,
你把我
no,
不
put both
把我
of us
我们俩
here.
都放下来吧
I can go back by myself.
我可以自己回去的
It's alright.
没关系
I can drive you back.
可以的
The fish you are saying
你说的那根稻草
is your old classmate
是你相亲遇到的
you met in blind date?
高中同学啊
Then what are you waiting for?
那还客气什么啊
It's time to show
是时候表演你
your real skills.
真正的技术
Take him!
抓住他
Do you
你想
want to take me?
抓住我啊
It's just that your scooter
不就是你的电动车
got busted.
被撞扁了嘛
Take it easy.
别激动
It wasn't my scooter got busted.
撞的根本就不是电动车
It was my dignity.
撞的是我的尊严
It wasn't my scooter squealed,
发出尖锐爆鸣的
but the heart
也不是小电驴
inside me.
是我的内心
Don't be so dramatic.
这事不至于
I'm telling you.
我跟你说啊
Such an elite
像现在
like him must have seen
他这种人类精英
countless top-notch women.
什么高精尖女性没见过
Just be yourself.
你就做真实的自己
Maybe that will make you
没准还能够另辟蹊径
special enough to get his attention.
成功吸引他注意力呢
Forget it.
算了
He and I are totally different.
我俩根本就不是一路人
Right.
行
But I should warn you.
那我可得提醒你啊
Your ex is coming back
你那个前男友
from abroad next week.
下周就要回国了
You're about to meet
你们即将在同学的
at a friend's pre-wedding party.
婚前派对上相遇
A Returnee student.
海归留学生
Doctor from private hospital.
私立医院的医生
Who said to make a handsome entrance
我记得当时好像是谁说
on the arm of a boyfriend
要挽着高他一头
who is much taller
秀他三倍的男朋友
and three times better, and to slap with
帅气登场的
her permanent employment contract
还有要拿着转正合同
into his face?
甩他一脸
Let me tell you, Xiaoning.
我跟你说啊 筱柠
What's happening now is that
现在这种情况呢
he's returning with academic excellence
就是人家学成归国
and a bright future.
硕果累累
And you?
但是你呢
Love and career,
爱情事业
you have neither of them.
两手空空
How are you going to catch up?
你该如何一雪前耻啊
I have my career!
我也没有两手空空呀
I can definitely be converted
转正的事情
to permanent.
我十拿九稳的
What about a boyfriend?
那男朋友呢
Gotta go.
挂了
Come on!
你快点啊
Left, left, left!
左边 左边 左边
Let me get a buff.
我就 我先拿个增益
Why are you
不是你抢我人头
stealing my kill?
干什么你
Okay, that's enough!
差不多就行了别玩了
You'd get me banned!
你这样会被封号的
Look at other people's parents.
你看看人家那父母
They're so anxious
自己家的孩子
about their kids
没有个对象
not having a date.
多着急呀
Can't you two learn something from them?
你们俩学学行不行啊
Introduce me to some boys!
给我介绍几个男朋友
"Some"?
还几个
Why don't you just kill me?
你要我这条老命算了
I can finally relief after retirement.
我这好不容易退休了
Now I still have to work for you?
我还得给你打工
I have squeezed clean
我那些
my square-dancing friends
跳广场舞的姐妹们
for information of boys.
都被我薅秃了
Now
现在
all that's left is Mr. Wu's nephew,
就只剩下吴老师
who just returned from abroad.
刚回国的外甥了
Mr. Wu has a nephew?
吴老师有个外甥啊
I'm telling you.
我跟你说啊
It's said that this young man
这个吴老师的外甥呢
never went on a blind date.
据说从来不相亲
He's got a good-looking face,
五官端正
a clean family background,
家世清白
good character
这人品能力
and ability.
那都是拔尖的
If you can meet him,
你要是能把他带回来
I'm sure you'll never
妥妥的
want to go on another blind date.
以后再也不想相亲了
Just one elite as him
像这种品相
is better than five ordinaries
那在相亲界
in the dating market.
那也是以一敌五的
So,
所以
have I
这个月
accomplished my KPIs
我的关键绩效指标
this month?
完成了吧
Don't push me
不要逼我
to introduce you boys again.
再给你介绍了啊
Give me his WeChat number.
先把微信给我再说
Okay.
行
I'm sending you his contact card.
那个我给你发过去了啊
On WeChat.
微信啊
Okay, okay.
好 好 好
Let me see.
我看看
Mom.
妈
If this boy is not
如果这个条件
as good as you said,
没有你说得那么好
he would not count
这个人就不算
and you have to introduce me another.
你要重新给我介绍一个
Ji Yuheng?
纪昱恒
No way!
不会吧
How can it be such a coincidence?
这也太巧
Mom, this...
妈 这
Mom!
妈
I can't handle this one.
妈这个我搞不定
Are there any other boys
还有没有其他
I don't know?
我不认识的
I admit he's hot.
帅是帅
But I really can't get this one.
可是这个真不行
Thank you.
谢谢啊
This blind date didn't work out,
虽然这次相亲没有结果
but I'm about to
但转正
get my permanent employment contract.
马上就要有结果了
Good morning.
您好
Please get a number first.
这边先取号
Ms. Zhang, you're so early today.
张姐您今天这么早
Ms. Li, yours is No. 10.
李姨 十号
Please go there to receive your pension.
您去那边窗口领退休金
Mr. Wang.
王叔
I've calculated
您的存款利率
your deposit rate.
已经算好啦
Thank you.
感谢啊
Good morning.
您好
How can I help you?
办什么业务
I want to make a deposit.
办理存款业务
Please get a number here.
这边先取个号
Okay.
好
Here you are.
你的
Isn't today the VP meeting?
今天不是副总会议吗
Why is Ji Yuheng here?
为什么纪昱恒会参加
I don't know.
这个不清楚
Please be seated.
大家都请坐
Please.
坐
Let's get started.
开始吧
This is the quarterly
季度营销数据统计
marketing statistics.
大家看一下
Foreign currency deposits
全年外币存款
increased by $326 million year-on-year.
增加了三点二六亿美元
By the end of last month,
截止上个月底
we have ￥25 million
我们代瑞银行
in microenterprise loans
小微企业贷款
and non-performing loans,
不良贷款两千五百万元
a reduction of ￥10 million
比去年同时期
from the same period last year.
减少了一千万元
Here's this quarterly
这是我们
balance analysis
这个季度存储量分析
of Bank of Dairui.
大家可以看一下
I'd like to ask Deputy Manager Qi.
我想问一下齐副经理
What is the cause for the ￥25 million
不良贷款两千五百万
in non-performing loans?
具体原因是什么
These loans
这些贷款
are initially vetted
在最初
and rated as
审核的时候
low risk.
都是风险系数很低的
But in the end, the borrower
但最后
ran away because the business
因为企业经营不善
went bankrupt
导致破产
due to poor business practices.
借款人跑路
We all know
这些也是大家知道
these are unpredictable.
不可预料的事情
You said they were unpredictable.
你说是不可预料
Then let me ask you
那我就问你一个
a predictable one.
可以预料的
Show me the information
这个借款人
from this one's background check.
背调信息是哪些
I thought today
我以为今天
was just a debriefing,
只是汇报
so I wasn't prepared.
没有准备
I'll do it
等稍后
right after...
我就
"Not prepared"?
没有准备啊
It's okay.
没关系
I've got it done for you.
我替你准备好了
I have a file with me.
我这里有一份资料
Ji Yuheng!
纪昱恒
At least we work together,
我们同事一场
do you have to be so cruel?
你有必要做这么绝吗
Leaving me no choice?
一点活路都不给我留
I've already given you the chance.
我已经给过你机会了
Let's look at this.
我们可以看一下大屏幕
Within these bad debts,
在这些坏账里面
there are 10 small businesses
贷款余额
with loan balances in excess
超过一百万的小企业
of one million RMB.
一共有十家
There are a total of three
贷款余额五百万的
with ￥5 million loan balances.
一共有三家
Among these 13 businesses,
而这十三家企业当中
the actual controllers
实际控制人
include
包括
but are not limited to,
但不限于
your friends from college,
你的大学同学
your distant relatives,
你的远房亲戚
and even
甚至还有
your virtual clients.
你的虚拟客户
How unpredictable.
还真是让人无法预测呀
We, as bank employees,
我们作为银行职员
have been given the right to
被赋予了
mobilize huge amounts of money.
操作巨额资金的权利
We should be using it for the good,
应该用它来帮助人
not to benefit ourselves.
而不是利己
You exceeded your KPIs?
超额完成关键绩效指标
Xiaoning,
筱柠姐
You're going to kill yourself
你这是要累死自己
and us!
卷死我们呀
What else can I do?
那要不然怎么办呢
Performance is my backbone.
业绩是我的底气
I must get permanent contract.
我得转正啊
If I couldn't get it,
如果今年还转不了的话
I wouldn't wait for another 3 years as an intern.
我可不能再熬三年了
Xiaoning.
筱柠姐
I glanced at the converting list
我刚去送报告的时候
on the big boss's desk
瞄了一眼大领导
when I was dropping off my report.
桌子上的转正文件
Your name is on it!
有你的名字
How are you going to celebrate?
怎么庆祝
You pick the restaurant.
地方你选
It's been three years.
三年了
Finally, I can ask you for an extortionate dinner.
终于心安理得宰你一顿
I'm calling you here
今天叫大家来
to announce
主要是宣布
new permanent members this year
年度的转正人员
and transfers.
以及相关的人事变动
Without further ado,
我也不多啰唆
here are the new
下面我宣布
permanent members of Dairui
二零二三年度
in the year of 2023.
代瑞银行转正的人员有
Han Meijuan,
韩美娟
Zhao Xiaojun,
赵晓军
and Tang Yuhui.
唐羽卉
Congratulations.
祝贺他们
In addition, there's a staff shortage
另外啊
in the Business Development Department.
由于拓展部门人手不够
The bank authorized
行里特批
the secondment
从大堂
from the lobby.
借调人员
to supplement.
补充人手
Tu Xiaoning.
涂筱柠
From today on, you'll work at
接下来你去拓展一部
Dept 1 of Business Development.
补充人手
There are
那边也有
better opportunities for you.
更好的工作机会
Good luck.
祝你前途似锦
Here's
下面
the highlights of
我说一下今天下午的
this afternoon's work.
工作重点
Sir.
主管
Why am I
为什么转正名单里
not in the list?
没有我
Tu.
小涂啊
You've been working here for three years.
你都在行里工作三年了
Why do you still ask
怎么还会问出
a question like that?
这样的问题
Just because
正是因为
I've been here for three years,
我在银行三年了
I have to ask.
我才问
I am a contractor,
虽然我是劳务派遣
but I have credentials.
但我已经考下三证
Speaking of reviews,
论评价
all my clients
我所有的客户
give me 5 stars.
给的都是优
Speaking of my attendance,
论考勤
I've never been
三年来
late for work or leave early
我从来都没有
in three years.
迟到早退过
Speaking of my performance,
论业绩
I've been in the top three
我每一次考核
on every assessment.
都是前三名
Tang Yuhui has
来行里
been here less than half a year,
不到半年的唐羽卉
and she's permanent now.
都转正了
How
所以
can I not be
为什么转正名单里
in the list?
没有我
Good question.
对呀
Why not you?
为什么不是你呢
Xiaoning.
筱柠啊
You've been working here long.
你在行里工作这么久了
Why can't you see
怎么还看不清
human network
资源和人脉
is far more important than hard work?
远远比勤奋更重要
Why is recruiting department called
招聘部门为什么叫
"human resources"?
人力资源部门
Because people
因为人
are a resource in themselves.
本身也是一种资源
I keep wondering
不知道为什么
why time flies
二十五岁以后
after the age of 25.
总觉得时间过得飞快
I've been trying so hard,
我兜兜转转
yet I still got nothing.
依旧一无所有
Maybe
或许
I can keep telling myself
我可以继续劝自己
just to watch the road underfoot,
做好当下
not the uncertain future.
不问前程
But the consequence of taking
但走一步看一步的后果
one step at a time
很可能是在
is to keep spiraling out of control
下一个三年里
for the next three years.
继续失控
I'm itching to do well in work and love.
我急于转正和相亲
Maybe it has nothing to do
或许压根
with "I'm a contractor"
与什么劳务派遣
or "my ex's about to return".
前男友无关
It's just me
只是我
being insecure and anxious
缺乏安全感的二十七岁
at 27.
焦虑而已
Mr. Zhong.
周总
Tell him I'll be there this afternoon.
你跟他说我下午过去
Okay.
好的
Nice to meet you.
你好
Are you
是
Tu Xiaoning?
涂筱柠吧
I was  informed by the lobby
大堂那边跟我说了
that you'll come.
你会过来
Feel free to ask me
你有什么不清楚的呢
if you have questions.
尽管问我
They call me
在拓展部啊
"The Walking Encyclopedia" in BD Dept.
我就是行走的百科全书
Oh,
对了
I'm Zhou Kai.
我叫周凯
Don't mistake it
记住啊
for "Zou Kai (go away)".
别叫我走开
Nice to meet you.
你好
Just kidding.
就是谐音梗
Relax.
轻松一下嘛
Could I know who's in charge here?
请问这边谁负责呀
Strictly speaking,
严格地来说呢
it's
是
good old Mr. Jiang.
老好人江总
But it's Jing
不过呀
who has the final say.
最终还是静姐说了算
Jing?
静姐
Yes.
就是你们
I'm sure you've heard of her.
都听过的那个啊
The queen in
拓展一部
Dept. 1 of Business Development.
山大王
The infernal bomb of Dairui.
代瑞银行一杆枪
The last woman standing
男人堆里
in the bloodshed.
厮杀出的独裁者
The most ambitious
野心写在了脸上的
iron lady.
职场女魔头
She rules with atrocity during the day,
白天残暴无道
and sleep without a partner at night.
夜晚孤枕难眠
She's a woman
大概率呢
who probably going to
这辈子会跟钱
marry Mr. Money
过一辈子的
for the rest of her life.
冷血女人
Isn't she?
是吧
Who?
谁呀这是
Who's making up rumors?
造谣生事呢
Jing.
静姐
I'll help catch the rumor mongers now.
我现在就帮你去查啊
How's that medical loan going?
那个医疗贷款怎么样了
The guy in charge
他们那个负责人
-is being very evasive. -I don't want to hear
推三阻四 我要听的
about your incompetence.
不是这些无能的理由
I want results, okay?
我要的是结果明白吗
I'm fetching you results right now.
我这就去跟进
What is our bank's Late Repayment
我行的逾期还款利率
Interest Rate?
是多少
It's 150%
正常利率的
of the normal rate.
百分之一百五
Good.
行
Come with me.
跟我来吧
I'm sorry.
不好意思啊
I'm actually here to resign.
我是来辞职的
Whatever. Come in now.
辞职也先进来吧
Are you done?
改好了吗
Not yet.
还没呢哥
Please wait.
您稍等一下啊
Excuse me.
不好意思
She's a fast worker.
这小姑娘干活挺麻利的
How did you talk her out of leaving?
你是怎么劝她不离职的
I didn't.
我没劝啊
The member of our department
本来咱们拓展部
needs to do three times of work.
就一个人要顶三个人用
Compliance Department has its eye on us.
合规部盯得又紧
I can't waste
这种免费的劳动力
such free labor.
不用白不用
Better make good use of her.
能用一天是一天
You're completely
你还真是吃了煤炭
heartless.
黑了良心
"Heartless"?
你有良心啊
I'm giving her a good lesson
这是在她离职之前
before she leaves.
给她狠狠地上了一课
She's lucky.
是她赚到了
You're still too young.
学着点吧你
Subsection III
第四条的
of article IV.
第三小节
Good luck.
加油
Jing.
静姐
Excuse me.
打扰一下
I've done the work
您让我做的工作
you asked me to do.
我做完了
Where do I put them?
放哪儿呢
Here.
拿来吧
Do you have a moment now?
静姐现在有时间吗
I need you to approve my separation request.
帮我批一下离职申请
Separation request?
离职申请
Don't you know non-staff personnel
你不知道编外人员
don't have to
是不需要
apply for separation?
办离职申请的吗
No one told me that.
没有人跟我说过
What's that look?
你现在什么表情
Are you feeling wronged?
委屈啊
You think the whole of Dairui
觉得整个代瑞
is rotten to the core,
都烂到骨子里了
and everyone's picking on you?
所有人都在欺负你是吗
No.
没有
I just think
我就是觉得
it has to be fair.
得公平
Fair?
公平
Fairness is for the courts,
公平是法院给你的
not for the workplace.
职场给不了你
Fifteen loan receipts.
十五张借款借据
You got two wrong.
你错了两张
Nine interest rate tables. You got one wrong.
九张利率表你错了一张
When I started working here,
我以前刚入职的时候
I woke up at 4:00 a.m. every day
每天四点起床
to memorize policies, laws and regulations.
背金融政策 法律法规
I thought I was working so hard.
我以为我起得很早
But it's never enough.
但是远远不够
There's always someone who works harder.
永远有人比我更早
I don't have a good reputation
在这个地方呢
in this place.
我风评不好
But I'm in charge.
但是我说了算
There's no paperwork
你的离职还有入职
for your leaving or joining.
不需要办任何手续
To complain and leave or to adapt.
抱怨离开还是适应规则
It's up to you.
你自己决定
I'll
我先
correct my mistakes first.
把东西改好了再说
Here.
拿走
Hello, Fang Xiao.
喂 方肖
Did you get the invitation to the party?
派对邀请函收到了吧
Yes.
嗯
Well,
那个
I'm sure I'll be dressed
你的婚礼
for your wedding,
我肯定会盛装出席
but I'll pass the party
但下周末那个婚前派对
next weekend.
我就不去了
I have work to do.
有别的安排
What work?
什么安排呀
Listen.
我跟你说
You haven't been
大学同学聚会
to college reunion yet.
你可还没有出席过
So
这次
you have to come this time.
一定得来
Okay.
行
I'll go next weekend.
下周末我会过去
You'll see me.
等我吧到时候
Okay.
好嘞
They say
都说
the Business Development Department
那个拓展部
is for those who's been frozen out.
是代瑞宁古塔
Why did you agree to go?
你为什么要答应去啊
I don't think so.
谁说的
I think BD Dept.
按理说拓展部
is more promising
是比大堂
than the lobby.
更有发展前途的
It's just Dept. 1 is
只不过最近
not doing well recently.
一部的情况不太好
I saw a lady today who was
我今天看到了一个人
particularly good.
特别厉害
I think I could learn
我觉得在她身上
a lot from her.
我能学到不少真本事
Never give up.
愈挫愈勇
That's the girl I know.
不愧是你
It isn't bad actually.
这样也好
We can
以后啊
continue to hang out in the same
我们就能在一个大厦
building.
继续厮混啦
This one's good.
这个也不错哎
Not good enough for you.
不够衬你
Why don't you find me one
那你倒是给我找一套
that suits me?
衬我的呀
I'm working on it.
我这不在找着呢吗
You're really going to go to that
你还真打算去那个
pre-wedding party?
婚前派对啊
Of course.
当然要去了
The bride is my friend.
新娘是我好朋友
I have to go.
我为什么不去呀
Besides,
再说了
I have to change
我发现我有个问题
from always being passive.
总是被动地迎接人生
No matter at work
不管是工作也好
or in love life,
或者爱情也罢
I was likely to
一遇到问题
take whatever they gave me.
我就选择且行且看
So easy-going.
随缘
But when the results came in
等到结果出来了
which weren't what I expected,
不合我自己的心意
I tended to be unhappy,
我就开始生气
or even mad.
甚至是恼火
I can't go like this.
我觉得这样不行
I'm going to start being proactive.
我要开始主动出击
Having a voice in my life.
迎接我的人生
Okay.
行
Anyway, I'll support you
总之不管你做什么决定
in whatever you decide.
我都支持你
But I've heard that
不过我最近可听说
Lu Sijing can't get you
这个陆思靖在国外
out of his mind when he's abroad.
一直忘不掉你
He's trying to woo you again.
他要重新追你
How about you?
你怎么想
Do you still love him?
还爱他吗
Happy birthday to you.
祝你生日快乐
Xiaoning.
筱柠
Happy birthday.
生日快乐
I'm sorry.
对不起
I'd like to intern abroad
我想在这里
for one more year.
再多实习一年
When you become a permanent
到时候你也转正了
employee, I'll give you
我一定补给你一个
an even bigger proposal.
更盛大的求婚
Xiaoning.
筱柠
Happy birthday!
生日快乐
Make a wish.
许个愿吧
Lu Sijing.
陆思靖
You're missing out on
你错过的
more than just a birthday proposal,
不只是一次生日求婚
but our future.
还有我们的未来
Ending a seven-year relationship
结束七年的恋情
was the best decision
才是我做过
I ever made.
最对的选择
How are you today?
今天还好吧
Isn't it
浪漫
romantic?
是吧
Ji Yuheng.
纪昱恒
You're dressed so well.
穿这么帅
Want to steal my spotlight?
抢我风头啊
No, handsome.
哪里敢
Happy wedding day.
新婚快乐啊
Thanks.
谢谢
The wedding is good.
确实弄得还不错
Yeah, isn't it?
还行吧
Fang Xiao.
方肖
Happy wedding day.
新婚快乐
Just in time.
来得正好
Let me introduce.
介绍一下
This is Ji Yuheng,
纪昱恒
graduated from Qingbei University,
清北大学毕业的高材生
now working at Compliance Department
现在在代瑞总行的
in Bank of Dairui Head Office.
合规部工作
This is Lu Sijing.
陆思靖
He just returned from aboard.
才留洋回来的
Doctor of Renji Hospital.
仁济医院的医生
Nice to meet you.
你好 陆思靖
We've met before.
之前我们见过
Really?
是吗
Nice to meet you, too.
你好 纪昱恒
Why are you being so formal?
这么生疏干什么
You are my friends
你们都是我
from different schools.
各个时期的同学
From now on,
以后呢
you can be friends, too.
大家都是好朋友了
Remember
没事啊
to invite me to dinner when you have time,
多出来请我吃吃饭
or I'll miss you so much.
省得我老想你们
Speaking of classmates,
说到同学
I really missed you guys.
还真挺想你们的
You did?
想念啊
I can't tell.
想念谁啊
After all, you didn't come to
那还这么多年
our reunions all these years.
不参加我们的同学聚会
Today's second female lead.
今天的第二女主角
She's not the same as she used to be.
她和以前不一样了
She's prettier, isn't she?
是比以前更漂亮了吧
It's something in her eyes.
是眼神
I'm here
今天我可是
on a mission today.
带着任务来的啊
You know
你们也知道
there's some misunderstanding
我和筱柠之间
between me and Xiaoning.
有些误会
So I'd like to use your place
所以我想借你这个地方
to formally apologize to her.
正式跟她道个歉
I'm going to get her back.
我打算重新追回她
Don't worry.
放心
Just as
就按照我们之前
we planned.
计划好的来
I'm sure it's fine.
肯定没问题
I'm going.
去了
What's Lu Sijing up to?
陆思靖要干吗呀
Didn't they break up a long time ago?
他们不是早就分开了吗
What is this?
这是在干啥
Ji Yuheng?
纪昱恒
What's he doing here?
他怎么也在这儿
Xiaoning.
筱柠
Long time no see.
好久不见
What are you doing?
你要干吗
I'm here to apologize.
我是来负荆请罪的
A year ago
一年前
on my birthday,
我过生日
you said you'd propose to me
你说会在我生日会上
at my birthday party.
跟我求婚
But you didn't.
结果你爽约了
You've already embarrassed me once.
已经让我很尴尬了
What are you doing today?
你今天这是干吗
You want to make it twice?
想让我更尴尬是吗
Xiaoning.
筱柠
I know it's too late
我知道有些话现在说
for these,
已经太晚了
but I have to tell you.
但是我必须要告诉你
A year ago, as you were looking
一年前你满心欢喜地
forward to our marriage
期待着我们的婚姻
and our future,
期待着我们的未来
I was a deserter.
可我却做了逃兵
At that time I felt
那时候的我觉得
getting married and starting a family then
当下结婚生子
was not the best choice.
不是最好的人生选择
It took me a year
可我经过这一年
to realize,
才彻底地明白
there's
爱
no way
是没有办法
to put a value on love.
用价值来衡量
That's why I'm here,
所以我今天
in front of our friends,
想当着所有同学们的面
to formally apologize to you.
正式地跟你道个歉
Xiaoning.
筱柠
I'm so sorry.
对不起
Please forgive me.
请你原谅我
Forgive him!
原谅他
Don't push her so hard!
你们别这么逼筱柠
It's her own choice.
怎么选择是她自己的事
Let her decide.
你们瞎起什么哄啊
Yeah!
就是
I still remember the day
那天陆思靖爽约的事
he went back on his word.
我都还记得呢
How can she forgive him so easily?
怎么能说原谅就原谅
Take the flowers back.
你赶紧把花收回去
Right now.
收回去
Xiaoning.
筱柠
I know you're still mad at me.
我知道你还在生我的气
Can you give me one more chance
再给我一次机会
to make it up to you?
让我补偿你好吗
You don't have to.
你不用补偿我
You don't owe me anything.
你也不欠我什么
I really can't live without you.
我真的不能没有你
You certainly can.
你可以没有我
From the moment
从你决定一声不响地
you decided to leave
不跟我说任何话
without a word,
就转身离开的那一刻起
you clearly knew it
你心里面就知道
that you'd be fine
没有我
without me.
你照样活得好好的
It's over.
我们俩已经结束了
Take the flowers back.
把花收回去
I won't take them.
我不会接你花的
What are you doing?
干吗呢 干吗呢
He's still confessing.
他还在表白呢
Do you not like my flowers,
你是不喜欢我的花
or do you not like me anymore?
还是不喜欢我了
What? What's going on?
什 什么情况
What's going on?
什么情况
Is Ji Yuheng
纪昱恒
into Tu Xiaoning?
不会喜欢涂筱柠吧
It's like
我这看着怎么像是
he's taking the heat off her.
替她解围啊
Ji Yuheng, huh?
纪昱恒 是吧
What do you want?
你想要干什么
You said you like it,
之前你说你喜欢它
so I bring it to you.
我给你带过来了
Isn't that our flower?
这不是我们的花吗
Silence.
听着就好了
It's pretty.
很好看
I like it.
我喜欢
What do you want?
我还没问你想干什么
This is something
这是我和筱柠
between me and her.
之间的事情
It's got nothing to do with you.
跟你有什么关系
Don't forget
你可别忘了
it's a pre-wedding party
今天是老同学的
of our friend.
婚前派对
If it gets ugly,
要是把事情闹得很难看
it won't be "something between you".
可就不是你们俩的事了
I've got my flower.
我手里已经有花了
I can't take yours.
接不了你的花
Lu Sijing.
陆思靖
Don't think
你不要觉得
I'm rejecting you today
我是因为跟你赌气
because I'm angry with you.
今天才拒绝你
I know what I want.
我想得很清楚
I just wish
我只是
I can see
希望可以看到
a better version of myself
未来更好的自己
and a better life in the future.
跟自己更好的人生
It's a pre-wedding party of our friend.
今天是老同学婚前派对
We are grown-ups.
大家都是成年人
Don't make it ugly.
真的别弄得太难看了
Okay.
好
Thank,
谢
thank you.
谢谢啊
Thank you for helping me out.
谢谢你帮我解围啊
It's okay.
不用谢
Looks like your last relationship
看来上一段感情
had a deep impact on you.
对你影响很深啊
No.
没有
I used to think that, too.
以前我也会这么想
I thought I'd be angry
我还以为我见到他
and hate him
会很生气
when I saw him.
很恨他
But actually, no.
但其实都没有
I,
我
I used to wonder
曾经还想过
if I'd still loved him.
我是不是一直爱着他
But the moment
但当我问出
I asked myself
自己这个问题
and I hesitated,
犹豫的那个瞬间
I knew I already had my answer.
我就知道答案了
Actually, I've always been
其实我一直介怀的
mad at him
应该是
for leaving
他不打招呼
without a word.
就离开
And
还有
I've always been mad at myself.
被抛弃的我自己吧
Sorry.
不好意思啊
I talked too much.
说这么多
So you go on blind dates
所以你去相亲
to get out of
也是为了尽快走出
the last relationship.
这段关系
I go on blind dates because I want to
我去相亲是想尽快地
find blue chip stock
找到一个
better than him
比他好
as quickly as possible.
超越他的绩优股
Actually, I've figured it out.
但其实我想明白了
I realize that
我才知道
all I wanted is
我想要的只不过是一个
a successful career,
事业有成
a stable job,
工作稳定
a happy family,
家庭幸福
and a visible future.
可以看得见的未来
Do you have
那之后呢
any plans now?
有什么打算吗
Probably keep going on blind dates.
继续相亲吧
If,
如果
I mean if.
我是说如果
If you just want
你只是希望有一段
a stable marriage,
稳定的婚姻关系的话
Will you,
你愿意
I mean,
我是说
will you marry me?
你愿意和我结婚吗
Tu Xiaoning.
涂筱柠
Time to go.
走了
Okay.
来了
Your turn,
到你了
Tu Xiaoning.
涂筱柠
Good morning.
先生您好
May I have your name please?
请问怎么称呼啊
I'm Ji Yuheng.
纪昱恒
Nice to meet you, Mr. Ji.
纪先生 您好
This is your Number Bear.
请领取您三十五号的
It's No. 35.
爱的号码熊
If you meet your Ms. Right,
如果遇到心仪的女士啊
you can exchange
可以凭
the bears of yours
您和对方手上的小熊
for
一起来兑换
the bigger one.
我们的大熊噢
This way, sir.
先生可以里边请
Thank you.
谢谢